<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: acknowledge | Danger Cove]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dangercove.com/blog/categories/acknowledge/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dangercove.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-24T11:27:56+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dangercove.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danger Cove]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easily add acknowledgments to your Xcode projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2014/05/29/easily-add-acknowledgments-to-your-xcode-projects/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-29T15:14:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2014/05/29/easily-add-acknowledgments-to-your-xcode-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you're working on a iOS or OSX app, you're bound to use a library, framework or other code that was generously shared by other people. The right thing to do (especially when the license requires it!) is to acknowledge that you're using their work in your app.</p>

<p>There are various ways to go about this, but I've just released <a href="https://github.com/DangerCove/Acknowledge/">a script called Acknowledge</a> that will make it very easy. It also works very well with <a href="https://github.com/DangerCove/DCOAboutWindow">DCOAboutWindow</a>, which I released earlier.</p>

<div class="thumbnail">
<a href="https://github.com/DangerCove/Acknowledge/"><img src="/images/content/acknowledge-acknowledgments.jpg" title="Acknowledgments" alt="Acknowledgments"></a>
</div>




<!-- more -->


<p>Acknowledge is a simple bash script that will easily generate a rtf that contains all the acknowledgments for libraries, frameworks and other code you've used in your iOS or OSX project.</p>

<p>It's made to work very well with <a href="https://github.com/DangerCove/DCOAboutWindow">DCOAboutWindow</a> and <a href="http://www.cocoapods.org">Cocoapods</a>. Acknowledge relies on <a href="http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown">MultiMarkdown by Fletcher Penny</a>.</p>

<p>You can <a href="https://github.com/DangerCove/Acknowledge/">read more about Acknowledge on GitHub</a>, or follow the setup guide below.</p>

<h2>Clone</h2>

<p>Clone the repo, preferably into the root of your Xcode project:</p>

<pre><code>$ git clone git@github.com:DangerCove/Acknowledge.git
</code></pre>

<p>Or if your project is a repo already, add it as a submodule:</p>

<pre><code>$ git submodule add git@github.com:DangerCove/Acknowledge.git
</code></pre>

<h3>Install multimarkdown</h3>

<p>Follow <a href="http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/install">the guide</a> on Fletcher's website, or if you're using homebrew:</p>

<pre><code>$ brew install multimarkdown
</code></pre>

<h3>Configure</h3>

<p>Copy acknowledge.cfg.default to acknowledge.cfg:</p>

<pre><code>$ cd Acknowledge
$ cp acknowledge.cfg.default acknowledge.cfg
</code></pre>

<p>Customize the paths to multimarkdown and your Pods folder if necessary.</p>

<h3>Add acknowledgments</h3>

<p>If you use Cocoapods and have your Pods directory setup, you are ready to go. Just run <code>acknowledge</code>.</p>

<pre><code>$ ./acknowledge
</code></pre>

<h4>Other acknowledgments</h4>

<p>Just add a markdown file to the <code>sources</code> directory and Acknowledge will handle the rest. Make sure the extension is <code>.md</code>.</p>

<h4>Order</h4>

<p>You might've notice the <code>10_</code> and <code>20_</code> prefixes in front of the files in the <code>sources</code> folder. Acknowledge will concatenate the files in order, so just add files and change to number to change the order.</p>

<p>The acknowledgments generated by Cocoapods will always be prepended with <code>10_</code>.</p>

<h3>Potential directory layout</h3>

<pre><code>.
|- Acknowledge/
|   |- acknowledge
|   |- ...
|   |- source/
|   |   |- 11_Vendor.md
|   |   |- 20_Acknowledge.md
|- Pods/
|   |- Pods-acknowledgements.markdown
|-  |- ...
|- Podfile
|- Coolproject.xcodeproj
|- Coolproject.xcworkspace
|- ...
</code></pre>

<h3>Test it</h3>

<p>Don't skip this step, you'll need to output in the next one.</p>

<p>Open a terminal window and run <code>acknowledge</code> once to see if it works, and to generate the initial <code>Acknowledgments.rtf</code>.</p>

<pre><code>$ ./acknowledge
</code></pre>

<p>Fix any errors and proceed.</p>

<h3>Add it to Xcode</h3>

<p>You'll probably want to show the acknowledgments somewhere in your app (have a look at <a href="https://github.com/DangerCove/DCOAboutWindow">DCOAboutWindow</a> if you're working on a Mac app, btw).</p>

<p>Simply add the generated <code>Acknowledgments.rtf</code> file to your project and display it somewhere.</p>

<h4>Generate the acknowledgments on each build</h4>

<p>Keeping your acknowledgments up to date is easy if you add Acknowledge as a build phase. Here's how that works:</p>

<ol>
<li>Open Xcode;</li>
<li>Select your project and open the <code>Build Phases</code> tab;</li>
<li>Click <code>Editor → Add Build Phase → Add Run Script Build Phase</code>;</li>
<li>Name your script something like "Update Acknowledgments" and position it so that it's above <code>Copy Bundle Resources</code>;</li>
<li>Now add the following code:</li>
</ol>


<p><code>cd Acknowledge &amp;&amp; ./acknowledge</code></p>

<p>(Make sure to adapt the paths if the script isn't located in the default folder.)</p>

<p>It should look something like this:</p>

<div class="thumbnail">
<img src="/images/content/acknowledge-buildphase.jpg" title="Acknowledge Build Phase" alt="Acknowledge Build Phase">
</div>


<p>That's it! Just build your project and you're set.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
