<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: adventures | Danger Cove]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.dangercove.com/blog/categories/adventures/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.dangercove.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-24T11:27:56+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.dangercove.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danger Cove]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control Your AirPlay Speakers Remotely With Porthole]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2015/04/28/remote-controlling-porthole/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-28T12:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2015/04/28/remote-controlling-porthole</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Being able to remotely control my AirPlay setup from the comfort of my couch has been at the top of my feature request list forever, so I'm very excited to say that <a href="http://www.getporthole.com/remote">it's now a feature in Porthole</a>!</p>

<p><img src="/images/content/porthole-remote.jpg" alt="Porthole Remote" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I've added Porthole to the collection of apps that work with the remarkable Unified Remote. Unified Remote is an app made by Unified Intents that allows you to remotely control many features of your Mac <em>and</em> a whole bunch of third-party apps, now including Porthole.</p>

<p>The remote lets you turn AirPlay speakers on and off, toggle the computer speaker and adjust the main volume from any iOS, Android and Windows phone or tablet that's on the same wireless network as your Mac.</p>

<div class="text-center">
<a href="http://www.getporthole.com" class="btn btn-large btn-success">Get Porthole!</a>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Features For Denied]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2015/01/08/more-features-for-denied/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-08T10:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2015/01/08/more-features-for-denied</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/content/denied-macbook-now-playing-with-caption.jpg" alt="Add songs from the Now Playing info" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.getdenied.com">Denied version 1.2.1</a> is out today, but last month I shipped a major update that I haven't posted about on here. It introduces awesome new features and a radical new design. Here's a short list:</p>

<ul>
<li>Skipping songs that contain explicit lyrics.</li>
<li>Skipping songs that you’ve heard before in the past few hours.</li>
<li>Seeing which song is currently playing and..</li>
<li>Adding rules straight from the Now Playing information.</li>
</ul>


<p>Also:</p>

<ul>
<li>The rules adding/editing interface has been completely revised.</li>
<li>Cool animations have been added.</li>
<li>Bugs have been fixed and things tweaked.</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<p>The best animation is probably the one you'll never see. It happens when you pause or un-pause your music player.</p>

<p><img src="/images/content/denied-animation-experiment.gif" alt="Animations in the latest build of Denied" /></p>

<p>The gif above also shows the flow of adding a new rule based on the song that's currently playing. The final version shows the amount of rules you've setup. Pretty neat.</p>

<p>Skipping repeating songs and tracks that contains explicit content are the two major new features. Both are disabled by default, but introduce powerful new methods to passively skip over music you don't want to hear.</p>

<div class="text-center">
<a href="http://www.getdenied.com" class="btn btn-large btn-success">Get Denied!</a>
</div>


<p>With the repeating song feature, you can set a timeout (between 30 minutes and 24 hours) and Denied will automatically skip over songs that have been played before in the set amount of time. I love this option when I listen to some Spotify Radio stations that have a limited amount of tracks.</p>

<p><img src="/images/content/denied-macbook-skip-repeating-with-caption.jpg" alt="Automatically skip repeating songs" /></p>

<p>The explicit content filter checks if songs are labeled as containing explicit lyrics. If you're listening with kids, or other sensitive ears, this feature will surely come in handy. Note that while it works with Spotify, Rdio and iTunes, the song has to be available in Spotify's library and you need to be connected to the internet.</p>

<p><img src="/images/content/denied-macbook-skip-explicit-with-caption.jpg" alt="Automatically skip explicit songs" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Denied Is On Sale And Now Supports Rdio &amp; iTunes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2014/10/07/denied-now-supports-rdio-and-itunes/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-07T14:48:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2014/10/07/denied-now-supports-rdio-and-itunes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Denied's version 1.1.0 is available for download. In addition to Spotify, it now automatically skip tracks in Rdio and iTunes as well! It also features an improved add-rule-flow that lets you create new rules much faster.</p>

<p>Get the update from the <a href="http://www.getdenied.com/appstore">Mac App Store</a>, or by checking for updates in <a href="http://www.getdenied.com">the trial version</a>.</p>

<p>Denied is on sale for a limited time for just <a href="http://www.getdenied.com/appstore">$2.99</a>, down from $6.99!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Denied, skip terrible music]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2014/09/17/denied-skip-terrible-music/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-17T12:45:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2014/09/17/denied-skip-terrible-music</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The wait is over! No longer do you need to listen to artists you can't stand on Spotify. And even better: you can automatically skip those annoying skits and bonus tracks on otherwise great albums.</p>

<p>Denied for Mac is <a href="http://www.getdenied.com">now available</a>!</p>

<p>Get your copy through the website or the Mac App Store and enjoy Top 40 playlists, the Christmas season and Spotify radio without the songs that you dislike.</p>

<p>Enjoy and let me know what you think on Twitter: <a href="https://www.twitter.com/deniedapp">@deniedapp</a>.</p>

<div class="thumbnail">
<img src="/images/content/denied-rulesoverview@2x.jpg" title="Denied rules overview" alt="Denied rules overview">
</div>




<!-- more -->




<div class="text-center">
<a href="http://www.getdenied.com" class="btn btn-large btn-success">Get Denied!</a>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reign in Your Bonjour Bookmarks]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2014/08/22/reign-in-your-bonjour-bookmarks/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-22T13:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.dangercove.com/blog/2014/08/22/reign-in-your-bonjour-bookmarks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new version of Reign just came out. Yes, really. And it even has a few cool new features (not a new theme though, sorry). I want talk one of them here: having Reign show up in Safari's Bonjour Bookmarks or Favorites.</p>

<div class="thumbnail">
<img src="/images/adventures/reign/screenshots/bonjour-bookmarks.jpg" title="Reign servers on the network automatically show up!" alt="Reign servers on the network automatically show up!">
</div>


<p>There's a magic menu in Safari, disabled per default, that will automatically show websites that announce themselves over <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bonjour_(software">Bonjour</a>. Bonjour is basically "a group of technologies that includes service discovery, address assignment, and hostname resolution". In short: it will let your Reign server show up in anyone's Safari, without needing to install Reign! Here's how to set it up.</p>

<!-- more -->




<div class="thumbnail">
<img src="/images/adventures/reign/screenshots/safari-preferences.jpg" title="Open Safari's preferences" alt="Open Safari's preferences">
<div class="caption">
First open Safari's preferences.
</div>
</div>




<div class="thumbnail">
<img src="/images/adventures/reign/screenshots/enable-bonjour.jpg" title="Click Advanced and then enable Bonjour Favorites" alt="Click Advanced and then enable Bonjour Favorites">
<div class="caption">
Click Advanced and then enable Bonjour Favorites.
</div>
</div>




<div class="thumbnail">
<img src="/images/adventures/reign/screenshots/show-favorites.jpg" title="Enable the Favorites bar" alt="Enable the Favorites bar">
<div class="caption">
Enable the Favorites bar.
</div>
</div>




<div class="thumbnail">
<img src="/images/adventures/reign/screenshots/bonjour-bookmarks.jpg" title="Reign servers on the network automatically show up!" alt="Reign servers on the network automatically show up!">
<div class="caption">
Reign servers on the network automatically show up!
</div>
</div>




<div class="text-center">
<a href="http://www.dangercove.com/reign" class="btn btn-large btn-success">Get Reign for Spotify!</a>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
